healthyrecipesblogs.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy | Healthy Recipes

This privacy policy applies to the following business: VDL, Inc and to your use of the website HealthyRecipesBlogs.com (“Website,” “Site,” or “Service.”)

Please read this statement carefully before proceeding to access this Site. Your use of this site indicates your agreement to abide by its terms. **If you do not agree with these terms, please do not use this Website.**

This privacy policy sets out how VDL, Inc. uses and protects any information that you give while using HealthyRecipesBlogs.com

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this Website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

VDL, Inc. may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy became effective on April 5, 2011, and was last updated on June 20th, 2019.

## Personal data

Personal data that we may collect about you relates to any information about a natural person that makes you identifiable, such as your name and email address. Specifically to our Site, unless you choose to email us and provide more information such as your name, the only personal information we collect is your email address when you choose to subscribe to our blog.

## Sensitive personal data

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to us. This includes but is not limited to your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, and criminal background. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Children’s Information

We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that we have personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13 in our database, please contact us immediately at HealthyRecipesBlog@gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## GDPR: What is a Data Controller?

For general data protection regulation purposes, the “data controller” means the person or organization who decides the purposes for which and the way in which any personal data is processed. The data controller is VDL, Inc. You can reach us at HealthyRecipesBlog@gmail.com

## GDPR: What is a Data Processor?

A “data processor” is a person or organization which processes personal data for the controller.

## GDPR: What is Data Processing?

Data processing is any operation or set of operations performed upon personal data, or sets of it, be it by automated systems or not. Examples of data processing explicitly listed in the text of the GDPR are: collection, recording, organizing, structuring, storing, adapting, altering, retrieving, consulting, using, disclosing by transmission, disseminating or making available, aligning or combining, restricting, erasure or destruction.

## Your rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)

  1. You have a right to request disclosure of the personal information we collected.
  2. You have a right to request disclosure of personal information sold or disclosed for a business purpose.
  3. You have a right to the deletion of your personal information.
  4. You have a right to opt out of the sale of your personal information.
  5. You have a right to data access and data portability.
  6. We are prohibited from discriminating against you for exercising your consumer right.
  7. We are obligated to notify you of your rights.

## What information do we collect about you and how?

VDL, Inc., as a Data Controller, is bound by the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). We are also bound by the requirements of the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA.”)

We may collect the following information:

### 1\. Personal information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by subscribing to our newsletter.

### 2\. Automatically-Collected Information

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

### 3\. Cookies

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

For more information, please visit allaboutcookies.org. You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above website tells you how to remove cookies from your browser.

You agree that we are entitled to obtain, use and process the information you provide to us to enable us to discharge the Services, including contacting you via email and analysis for website improvement purposes.

### 4\. Analytics

We use Google Analytics to store information about how visitors use our Website so that we may make improvements and give visitors better user experience.

Google Analytics is a third-party information storage system that records information about the pages you visit, the length of time you were on specific pages and the website in general, how you arrived at the site and what you clicked on when you were there. **These cookies do not store any personal information about you eg name, address, etc and we do not share the data.** You can view their privacy policy here. You may opt out of Google Analytics via ****[Google Analytics’ opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

### 5\. Feedblitz.com

We use this service for delivery of email updates and newsletters. Feedblitz stores your email address for the purpose of delivering such communications. **You may unsubscribe at any time and ask for your contact information to be removed from the Feedblitz database**. Please refer to [Feedblitz’ privacy policy](https://www.feedblitz.com/privacy/) for further information. **We do not store your personal information anywhere other than on Feedblitz.**

### 6\. Recipe Maker

We use this service, among other things, to enable user ratings of our recipes. Recipe Maker has provided us with the following information:

Cookies: When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

IP Address: When user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

How long we retain your data: Our cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

### 7\. Advertising

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements.

In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and we disclaim all liability in connection therewith.

You may use [this page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) to opt out of interest-based advertising.

### 8\. AdThrive Advertising

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive has provided us with the following information:

AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our Website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third-party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents: If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

### 9\. IP addresses

An IP or Internet Protocol Address is a unique numerical address assigned to a computer as it logs on to the internet. VDL, Inc. does not have access to any personally identifiable information and we would never seek this information. Your IP address is logged when visiting our site, but our analytic software only uses this information to track how many visitors we have from particular regions, and Recipe Maker as detailed above uses it to prevent rating spam.

### 10\. Sucuri

This Site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan. For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

## Who we may share your information with

We may share your information with third-party companies that function on our behalf. Examples include, but are not limited to, companies that assist us with serving advertisement on the Site (such as Adthrive.com), analyzing data (such as Google Analytics), and providing marketing assistance (such as Feedblitz.com) or technical assistance. We may share information about you that they need to perform their functions.

## How will we use your information and why?

At VDL, Inc. we take your privacy seriously and will only use your personal information to provide the Services you have requested from us. We will only use this information subject to your instructions, data protection law and our duty of confidentiality.

Our lawful reason for processing your personal information is “A legitimate interest” eg to respond to your request to receive emails from us. We collect information on our website to process your inquiry and send you emails and newsletters. **We do not sell personal information and will not share your information for marketing purposes with other companies** so that they may offer you their own products and services.

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  1. To operate and maintain the Website;
  2. To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  3. To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  4. To respond to your inquiries;
  5. To track and measure analytics and advertising on the Website;
  6. To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

Except when required by law, **we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent** ; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets.

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you, or data combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

You may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user.

## Transferring your information outside of Europe

As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you give to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). We and some of our third-party providers are located outside of the EU. Specifically, this Website is hosted in the United States.

By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU to give you those services.

## Security precautions in place about data collected

When you give us personal information, we take steps to make sure that it’s treated securely. Our Website is encrypted and protected with the following software: DV SSLs from Let’s Encrypt. When you are on a secure page, a lock icon will typically appear on web browsers.

Non-sensitive details such as your email address are sent normally over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

## Marketing

If you have consented to receive marketing by subscribing to our blog, we will send you information about new blog posts, or other emails and newsletters which may be of interest to you. You may opt out at any point as set out below. You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. To opt out please email: HealthyRecipesBlog@gmail.com, or use the “Unsubscribe” link on any email you receive from us.

## How long will we hold your data for?

GDPR requires us to retain personal data no longer than is necessary for the purpose we obtained it for.

We will hold your personal data that you voluntarily gave to us, eg name and email for marketing purposes, for as long as you wish to continue receiving emails from us. With each email you receive from us, you will have the opportunity to opt out by unsubscribing.

As for information collected by Google Analytics, we have set our user data retention period to the shortest offered, which is 14 months.

## Access to your personal information and the right to be forgotten

You can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. To exercise this right, Please email HealthyRecipesBlog@gmail.com.

Generally, this will simply include your email address, as this is the only personally identifiable information we collect on this Site through Feedblitz.com.

The right to remove information does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Complaints

If you feel that your personal data has been processed in a way that does not meet the GDPR, you have a specific right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority in your country. The supervisory authority will then tell you of the progress and outcome of your complaint.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on June 20th, 2019 to include the CCPA guidelines.

## How to contact us

Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you: HealthyRecipesBlog@gmail.com.
